[instrumental theme music playing]
You didn't have to, you know...
-I know. I just thought--
-Since you were leaving.
Is it wrong to want to say goodbye
to my sister?
You know I'd bring you if I could.
Let's not ruin things
with a bunch of lies, Jess.
-I'm just trying--
-To apologize?
Why would I apologize
for being a productive member of society?
Oh, there's the girl I know.
At some point, you have to
take responsibility for your choices.
Coming from someone
who's never had to make any.
-[Jess] That's not fair.
-Ah.
Your college wasn't paid for?
Dad didn't leave you the business?
What? And he should have left it to you?
You're a criminal, June.
I've made mistakes.
And I'm glad you recognize that.
But they don't want mistakes
in the new world.
Well, thanks for the meal.
Have a nice flight.
Oh. Wait.
I didn't ask you here to fight. I just...
I just wanted to give you these.
My house. My car.
I'm not gonna need them anymore, so...
I don't deserve this.
No, no. Start fresh.
Be a better version of yourself.
[scoffs]
-I could live here?
-[chuckles]
Yes.
I could drive your car?
-Wear your clothes?
-If you'd like.
So I could just... I could just be you?
[exhales]
[gasps softly]
[thunder rumbles]
[wind howling]
[indistinct chatter]
[Maureen] Yeah.
I was looking at it...
I was looking for anything to orient us.
Anything familiar,
a planet or a constellation.
But there was nothing, nothing--
There was nothing I recognized at all.
[Judy] Okay. I don't understand.
Exactly how lost are we talking about?
Yeah, "Can't find your car
in the parking lot" lost?
Well, if this is Earth
and this is Alpha Centauri,
we are, metaphorically, maybe,
a 600-year drive away.
Maybe.
Okay, so, not metaphorically...
Trillions of light years. It's, uh...
Look, if we got here, we can get back.
So... how do we get back?
Honestly, unless the Resolute is intact
and can find us,
we might be stuck here.
Which is why I need everyone
working on the problem.
-[John] Maureen.
-Okay?
We need to get comms operational.
Can't do that until we get the ship
out of the ice.
-Judy, you need to get--
-Maureen.
What?
-I think we should take a breather.
-[Maureen] What?
[John] With the storm outside,
there's nothing we can do,
and I think we'd all think a lot clearer
after some rest.
-I am kind of tired.
-Yeah. I think we all are.
Just an hour, Mom. Then I'll be ready.
Okay.
Okay. I will wake everybody up
after the storm.
Thanks, Mom.
[storm rumbling, ice crackling outside]
[sighs]
-Oh, no, Doctor, don't. I've got it.
-Oh, please. Let me.
Thank you.
[Smith sighs]
Um, your family...
Unfortunately, I...
I had to leave them behind.
Oh.
No, it's okay.
No husband, no kids.
Makes it a little easier.
You're welcome to stay with us until...
[chuckles nervously]
[stammers]
Let me show you
where you can store your stuff.
Doctor, engineer, soldier.
Sounds like I was rescued
by the right family.
I wouldn't say we're...
-It's complicated.
-Most families are.
[beeping]
-I'm a psychologist.
-Oh.
I actually specialize in family therapy.
You've come to the right place.
Seriously, if there's anything I could do
to repay you somehow...
Don't worry, we'll put you to work.
Um, so, you can store your stuff in there.
I'm sorry we don't have extra bunks,
but there's, uh, blankets.
Please. I'll manage.
Okay. See you in a bit.
See you. Good night.
[ice crackling against hull]
[sobbing]
[exhales]
[buttons beep]
[treadmill whirring]
[John] It's fine.
It's just the ice shifting.
I thought you needed the rest.
[sighs] I needed to relax.
There's a difference.
-[beeps]
-[treadmill powers down]
Hey, hon. Look...
what you went through out there
in the ice...
I know what that kind of fear
can do to your body.
More importantly,
what it can do to your mind.
-So, if there's anything you need to--
-[beeps]
I'm fine, Dad.
[treadmill whirring]
Okay.
You do what you have to do.
-[beeps]
-[treadmill stops]
[panting]
[wind howling]
[ice crackles against hull]
[slithering, low howling]
[screaming]
[gasping]
You okay?
[gulps] Yeah.
Bad dream?
[Will] Sort of.
Don't tell anyone, but I still get them
from time to time.
And when I do,
it helps to say what they were out loud.
It was nothing. Really. I'm fine.
[heavy footsteps]
[whispers] I thought you said
it wasn't dangerous.
I'm gonna go back to bed.
Sorry.
Please don't mention anything to my dad.
-Oh.
-About my nightmare.
I'm good at keeping secrets.
[loud rumbling]
-[Maureen shouting] Will?
-In here, Mom!
-Hey, is everyone okay?
-[Smith] Uh...
[Judy] What happened?
[Smith] I don't know.
It was like something just hit us.
It's the glacier. It's breaking apart.
-When the girls used the blast jets--
-Wasn't me.
Yeah. It wasn't her who totally saved
everybody's life.
[scoffs]
If we don't get the Jupiter out of here,
the whole thing's gonna collapse on us.
The storm's over. It's all clear up there.
Okay. Judy, pre-flight checklist.
Start with the thrusters.
Penny, as we get closer to the surface,
I want you on the radio.
Soon as we get the signal, we broadcast.
See if the Resolute--
-[John] Maureen.
-What?
We got a problem with the engines.
What kind of problem?
We don't have any.
-[John sighs]
-It's heavy particulate from the storm.
[Maureen scoffs]
It's blocking the air flow
to the ventilation shafts.
We're not going anywhere
until we clear this out.
-I'll get Judy to come down and start--
-Wait, you think she's ready?
What do you mean, ready?
After what happened,
you're not worried about her?
I'm worried about a lot of things,
Judy's not one of them.
She'll pull through. She always does.
Well, maybe she'll pull through faster
if we let her sit this out.
You know, give her time--
We don't have time, John.
This part of the glacier is--
Unstable. Yeah, I know.
So is our daughter.
You really think you're the best judge
of what she can and can't handle?
Look, I know you and the kids
are this team, but...
[sighs] ...if I'm gonna be here,
you gotta let me be here.
All right. Um...
Then how do you think
we should handle our new guest?
Well, it seems to want to help us,
but we don't know why it's here, or what--
I meant Dr. Smith.
Oh. Yeah, right. Um...
Well, if she qualified for Alpha Centauri,
she must be trained
in emergency procedures,
so she should be fine.
Okay, aft engine cage.
We need to disassemble
the contaminated thrusters.
So bag and heat-seal anything
that needs to be on VC levels.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. Sure.
How about you and I work together?
Okay, everybody else pair up.
-Dibs on Will.
-Seriously?
I want to spend quality time
with my brother. What's wrong with that?
[Maureen] You guys are on detox.
Every piece needs to be wiped completely
clear before it goes into the cage.
Guess you're with me.
Hey, you two,
flush out the combustion chamber
so we don't re-circ any contaminants
into the system.
Uh, John, does that sound okay?
Sure. Let's get this done.
Um... Okay.
Your robot's totally gonna
do the work for us, right?
[Maureen] You go ahead.
I'm gonna print a few replacement parts.
[Smith] Okay.
Is it safe?
I think that's the first time
I've ever heard you ask that.
Well, you haven't been around
to hear much of anything, so...
Hey, Jude?
It's okay if you don't want
to come down here.
Mom always says four hands
are better than two.
Doesn't she also say
"too many cooks spoil the broth"?
Not one time.
[chuckles]
[Maureen shouts] John?
Speaking of which...
Hey. Everything okay?
Did you use the printer today?
No. Why?
A record came up.
Someone ran a program outside protocol.
Oh. So you automatically assume it was me?
Not assuming. I'm asking.
Okay, I did think about it,
but it wouldn't let me.
Jesus, John.
This isn't your commune on Alpha Centauri.
We need protection.
You know how I feel about weapons
in our house.
We already have one, Maureen.
It belongs to an 11-year-old boy
and we have no idea how to use it.
-It's protecting Will.
-[scoffs]
After everything that's happened,
I'm relieved.
It's one less thing
we have to worry about.
More importantly,
if you didn't print something, who did?
We can skip the heat exchanger,
but let's pull the rotary coupling
and the igniter.
[Smith] Okay.
I have to be honest with you
about something.
And if it makes you regret taking me in,
I wouldn't blame you.
I was actually gonna ask you.
How did you get past the restrictions?
What do you mean?
On the printer.
There's a firewall so people can't--
I think our signals are crossed.
I haven't touched your printer.
Oh.
Sorry.
-What was it you wanted to ask?
-It's just that, uh...
my grasp of emergency training
isn't what it should be. Uh...
Most of my prep-grouping
was occupational and not familial,
and most of them
were more mechanically inclined,
so I figured they would...
[stammers] I'm sorry. I...
I really should've paid more attention.
I just never imagined we'd end up--
Hey, it's okay. Nobody did.
Really? You seem like you've been
preparing for this since you were a child.
Might explain why
I didn't have a lot of friends.
-[Smith] Oh, stop it.
-No, seriously.
[Smith] Look at you.
Successful, intelligent, beautiful.
You remind me of my sister.
I didn't have any siblings.
It would've been nice.
Someone to help with the chores,
work the fields.
Work the fields?
Am I standing next to a genuine farm girl?
-In the flesh.
-Oh.
Not a lot of farm girls
grow up to be aerospace engineers.
-Well, when you wish upon a star...
-[sighs]
♪ Makes no difference who you are ♪
[laughs]
[alert beeping]
What the hell is that?
-[Maureen] What's going on?
-[John] Fuel level's dropping,
which is weird 'cause we're not using any.
Damage from the ice
could've caused a leak.
I'll go check it out.
Keep an eye on the fuel.
If it drops any faster, radio me, okay?
[Judy] Okay.
Me, too.
[ice crackling outside]
[sobbing]
Your mom said
you'd know what to do with this?
Uh, yeah, that's fine.
Just leave it there. Thank you.
What do you think about her?
Dr. Smith? I don't know.
-I don't know. I like her hair.
-That's how you form your opinion?
What about judging a book by its cover?
Whoever said that
has never been to a bookstore.
You've never been to a bookstore.
The last one closed in--
That's not my point.
[footsteps receding]
Hey, come back.
These parts aren't gonna clean themselves.
Yeah, thank you. Cool robot, Will.
[device beeping]
Well, if there is a fuel leak,
it's not wide scale.
I'm gonna take a closer look.
[soft squeaking]
[soft slithering]
Thanks. So, new development.
Somewhere along the line,
we started bleeding fuel.
[pants] What do we do?
[grunts] Same thing we've been doing,
only a lot faster.
How much longer do you think we have?
Until we run out of fuel
or until the glacier crushes us?
Seriously, why don't we all
pile into that Chariot
and get the hell out of here
before it's too late?
Not a chance.
Maybe one or two people
could survive in there for a bit,
but not all of us. [grunts, panting]
I'm gonna take these to the kids
and see how they're doing on those parts.
[Maureen] Okay, great.
[grunts]
[soft slithering]
[Will] Hey! What are you looking for?
Come on.
I thought you were supposed to
listen to me.
[slithering continues]
[ship creaking]
-[slithering continues]
-What's... What's that sound?
-[rumbling]
-[screaming]
[Will] No!
[faintly] Mom!
[Will pounds on door, screams]
[Penny] Will?
[Maureen] Will!
-Where's Will?
-I don't know.
[robot] Danger, Will Robinson.
What kind of danger?
-Mom, be careful!
-Why? What happened?
There's something on the ship.
[John] Okay. We definitely got a leak.
-I'm just, uh, trying to find the...
-[device beeping]
-[beeping intensifies]
-...source.
Dad?
[Maureen] John?
John?
Joh-- Where's your father?
I... I think he's still in the basement.
Why? What's wrong?
Will said there's something on board.
Some kind of--
Some kind of what?
Judy, you go find Dr. Smith.
Penny, you stay here and--
[screaming]
Don't go downstairs.
[panting]
-Is it dead?
-[sighs]
-It is now.
-[Penny] Okay.
-What is it?
-And why does it smell so bad?
No idea, but it probably came in through
one of the puncture holes from the crash.
-Think it's been hiding the whole time?
-Yeah.
Smells like it's been hiding
in someone's butthole.
I've never seen anything like it.
[grunts]
Wait, where's Will?
It's okay. He's safe.
The robot locked him in the closet.
Okay.
-Why?
-Why does he do anything?
I think that smell is fuel.
Makes sense.
I found it in the water next to the tank.
[loud beep]
[automated voice] Warning.
Fuel level at 52%.
Fuel's dropping. Faster now.
And I'm never having unagi again.
[sniffs]
Our fuel isn't leaking. It's being eaten.
Our fuel is a methane hybrid.
One of the compounds must be similar
to its food source on the planet.
Any ideas how we get out of this one?
I need a bigger whiteboard.
Are those our fuel tanks?
Is anyone else
never sleeping in here again?
Is it just me?
The Jupiters were built
with two fuel tanks:
the primary and the reserve.
So far, our reserves are untouched.
If it stays that way,
we'll have enough to get out of the ice.
So we need to trap those things
and keep 'em out of the other tank.
Yes, but the emergency settings
will open the reserve tank
when the primary gets too low,
and the only way to stop that
is to turn it off manually at the source.
So, um, we have to go down
where the eels are?
At the rate these things are going,
we have about 15 minutes before we're dry.
I'll handle the tank.
You just get us ready to fly.
Hey, Dad?
-Yeah?
-I can help.
Oh, it's okay. You sit this one out.
No, seriously, I'm... I can handle it.
I believe you, I do.
I want you to believe it, too.
[ice crackling against hull]
-[breathing heavily]
-[ship creaking]
I need to get in there.
[robot] Danger, Will Robinson.
I know it's dangerous.
It's gonna get a lot more dangerous
if I can't get in there
to get a torque wrench.
Will, can you tell your robot
to open the damn door?
I've been trying. He won't listen.
[sighs] Judy.
[Judy] Yeah?
Judy, I need you to print me
a torque wrench, 11/16".
-[Judy] That's gonna take--
-I know.
-Mom said we've only got--
-I know. Can you just do the best you can?
-What are you gonna do?
-[sighs]
I'm gonna buy us some more time.
[Will] I just...
I don't understand.
It's okay. It's not your fault.
He usually does what I want him to do.
Really?
Why do you think that is?
I don't know.
Maybe it's his way of saying thank you.
For what?
For saving his life.
And now it's like we're connected.
Like he just knows what I want him to do.
Until now.
Maybe he's not listening to your voice...
because he's listening to what's inside.
What do you mean?
Every day, we have these little battles
going on inside of us,
between what we want to do...
and what we need to do. And...
sometimes they can be
very different things.
[automated voice]
Level three access confirmed.
Morning.
[Smith] Good morning.
[automated voice]
Level three access confirmed.
Excuse me, miss?
[automated voice]
Level three access confirmed.
Hey, Jessica Harris,
I've been looking for you.
Hey, come on, why aren't you stopping?
I'm sorry, I...
No, I'm sorry.
I just haven't been able
to get away from Holly lately.
At this point,
I don't even care if she finds out.
I just need to be with you.
Jesus, Jess.
I thought you'd been avoiding me.
-Can we go somewhere?
-I don't want anyone to see us.
Wait a minute.
[gasping]
-Who the hell are you?
-Let's make a deal.
You don't tell anyone about me,
and I won't tell your wife
about your bad taste in women.
-[grunts]
-[beeps]
[automated voice] Access granted.
-[man grunts]
-Stand clear.
[shrieks]
-Air lock releasing in ten seconds.
-[man] You don't wanna do this.
[automated voice] Press to override.
-Nine, eight...
-Press the button.
-You don't want to do this to me.
-...seven, six,
-five, four, three...
-Just press the override button.
-...two, one.
-Please, override it!
-[air lock releasing]
-[man screams, stops]
[Smith gasps]
[wind howling]
[ship creaking]
[Maureen] Salt for the eels.
Clever. Sixth grade biology?
[Penny] Close. Fifth grade.
It was actually Jimmy Sewerth's backyard.
You told me I couldn't play with him
because anyone who tortures worms
is destined to be a future serial killer.
Right. Well, Jimmy's not going
to Alpha Centauri, is he?
Your dad thinks I expect too much
of you kids sometimes. Do you?
Um... no.
[stammers]
I don't think you expect too much from us.
I just think maybe, sometimes,
you expect too little from Dad.
[grunts] Hey, Judy. How's it going?
Every time you ask, it goes faster.
Okay, so not yet. [coughs]
Are you okay?
[grunts] Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
[exclaiming]
Hey, Maureen.
How are the engines coming along?
-One down, one to go.
-Great.
[grunting] Oh!
I think some of these pieces
are still back in the hub.
-Do you want me to get them?
-Yeah. But be careful.
Mmm-hmm.
What... What are you doing?
I'm being careful.
[shouts]
[panting]
[exhales]
What are you looking at?
-[ice crackling against hull]
-[ship creaking]
[loud rumbling]
[gasps]
[grunting]
[gasping]
[automated voice] Surface unstable.
[Maureen] Hey.
-Hey! You okay?
-Yeah. You?
[scoffs] Sure. Judy, you okay?
[panting]
Yeah.
But the torque wrench, it didn't print.
[automated voice] Auxiliary tank released.
[John] Don't worry. It's okay.
-John...
-Judy, hold a sec.
When the Jupiter's weight shifted,
it must've exposed the fuel sensor
and released the reserves
into the main tank.
[sighs] That's all the fuel we have left.
Now they got it.
We can't wait. We gotta launch right now.
The last thruster's almost done.
I just have to secure it.
-So...
-Five minutes, tops.
[Penny, faint] Dad!
Penny?
[Penny] Dad, help!
-[Maureen] Penny!
-Something's wrong.
Whatever it is,
I'm sure your family will--
-They need me!
-[Maureen] Where are you?
-[Will] Do something! Please!
-[John] Penny!
Why won't you listen to me?
Please, help them.
[John, distant] Penny, where are you?
I don't understand.
Why won't he listen to me?
Shh. Deep breaths.
Fear is a powerful emotion, Will.
If you and that machine
are as connected as you say,
he can sense that fear in you.
It's okay to be afraid.
To want to save yourself.
No, it's not.
Self-preservation is nothing
to be ashamed of.
It's how we learn to survive.
[rumbling]
[gasping]
Help.
[gasping] Mom.
Dad!
Dad.
Hey, sweetie. You okay?
Been better.
Yeah, that's going around.
They're all around me. I can't move.
[screams] Oh, my God!
-Hey! Hey!
-No!
It's on my leg!
-[screaming] No! It hurts, Dad.
-Sweetie, it's okay.
They're not after you,
they're after the fuel.
But the fuel is... It's all over me!
Sweetie, it's gonna be okay.
[Penny] How do you know?
Daddy?
-Daddy? Daddy, no!
-Go! Go!
Go to the hub. Come on! Come on!
-[panting] Are we gonna die in here?
-No.
-Are you sure?
-'Course I'm sure.
You and me, we're survivors, aren't we?
[automated voice] Warning.
Fuel level at 45%. No reserves.
[sighs] Here's what I think.
Your family, they risked their lives
out there in the storm to save me.
So I think it's time I risked my life
to save them.
I don't understand. We're in here.
How are you gonna get out there?
Your robot! Think about it.
He only cares about putting you in danger.
He could care less what happens to me.
But I care what happens to you.
[chuckles]
I appreciate that, Will. I really do.
But one thing you'll learn about me...
I can handle myself.
Come on, tell him.
Robot, I'm gonna need you to listen.
[printer whirs, dings]
[gasping]
[exclaiming]
Okay.
[yells]
[panting]
[chuckling]
Okay! Okay!
-My mom and dad, make sure they're--
-[Smith] I will.
-[Will] And my sisters--
-Don't worry.
I got this.
[automated voice] Warning.
Fuel level at 30%. No reserves.
[ice crackling]
Warning. Fuel level at 25%. No reserves.
[automated voice] Ejection initiated.
This operation will compromise
the structural integrity
of your residential transport vehicle.
Further aerial navigation
will be eliminated.
29, 28, 27, 26...
Oh, come on.
Oh, no.
Come on!
[grunts]
Oh! Come on!
[both grunting]
[gasps]
Oh, thank God! [exhales]
Oh, thank you.
Okay, okay.
We're good. Let's go.
You look terrible.
Thanks. You, too.
Okay.
-Where the heck have you been?
-Figuring out how to save your ass.
[chuckles] And she's back.
[automated voice]
Warning. Fuel level at 15%.
That's okay.
15% should be enough to get us out.
-But what about those things?
-They should just burn up on ignition.
Everyone hold tight.
-[grunts]
-[engine powering down]
-[Maureen] You've gotta be kidding me.
-What's wrong?
-Nothing. We should be--
-[automated voice] Warning. Fuel at 10%.
-No reserves.
-Everything checks out.
[Penny gasps] We're gonna get crushed.
What do we do?
-Dump the fuel.
-What?
-We can't, we need--
If those things are still in the tank,
they might be clogging the intake valve,
which means
whatever fuel is left down there
can't get into the combustion chamber.
Ever drink fresh lemonade
and get a seed stuck in your straw?
[stammers] I know, Judy, it's just--
[automated voice] Warning.
Fuel level at 8%. No reserves.
[Judy] Trust me.
There's still enough fuel in the lines
to get us out.
Do it.
[automated voice]
Fuel ejection system... activated.
Maureen, does this thing run on fumes?
I sure as hell hope so.
[Penny] Dad?
[Judy] Dad, watch out!
[grunts]
[Penny exclaims]
[engines sputtering]
-John...
-It's okay, I got this.
[warning alarm beeping]
John?
-[Penny] Dad?
-Brace yourselves.
-[all yelping]
-[John grunting]
[Maureen] You okay?
[all panting]
Does anybody have a mop?
I may have barfed a little.
[laughs]
[Maureen] It's beautiful.
Nice bit of flying you did.
It's a good crew.
[Penny] We've got comms. They're live!
-[man] This is Mark on Jupiter 22...
-[Maureen] There are other survivors.
-[man 2] We have established...
-[Maureen laughs] We're not alone.
-[Mark] Standby.
-[Maureen laughs]
-[radio chatter continues]
-Wait a sec. Will. Will. Will!
Will?
Mom!
I'm so sorry I wasn't there to help.
It's okay, sweetie.
You would've if you could've.
[Penny] Guys! Guys, come here! Quick!
-What?
-[radio beeps]
[man] This is Captain Radic broadcasting
from the Resolute.
We've taken on heavy damage,
but are still operational.
Life support systems have been stabilized.
Navigational capabilities
are being assessed.
Wounded are being tended to.
Most importantly, we believe, in time,
we'll be able to get back on course
-toward our new home on Alpha Centauri.
-[screams]
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you!
[laughing]
-[Radic continues indistinctly on radio]
-[Judy] Mom, Mom, Mom!
I know, baby.
[Radic] And for those of you
who are unable to return,
know that as soon as repairs
are completed,
we will find you.
Did you really think we wouldn't find you?
Do you think you're the first person
who thought they could fake their way
into a new life?
June Harris. Quite a career.
Breaking and entering.
Possession of stolen goods.
Identity theft.
Now it seems you've graduated
to the big time.
We have you on camera
taking that man's life.
I was defending myself.
It wasn't my fault.
You don't actually believe that, do you?
Well, Miss Harris, I have some good news
and some bad news.
The good news, we haven't set up
a system of justice yet.
No courts. No jail.
Bad news?
We haven't set up a system of justice yet,
which means I can do
whatever the hell I want to you.
[door opens]
-[man] Sir, we've had a breach.
-What kind of a breach?
I don't know. They're asking for you
in the control room.
Sit tight. We are not done.
Not even close.
-[door closes]
-[alarm blaring]
-[explosions in distance]
-[people screaming faintly]
[thudding mechanical footsteps]
What is it?
What are you doing with that?
I don't want it.
Wait. Did you make it?
With our printer?
Why?
[robot] Danger, Will Robinson.
Danger? From what?
That was just a bad dream.
Look...
I know you don't want to hurt me...
but if we're gonna be friends,
you can't hurt anybody.
Ever.
Do you understand?
Good.
[dramatic music playing]